Harry F. Brown Papers
© 2003 University of Connecticut
- Series II: Photographic Prints (Black & White), n.d., 1930, 1931
  - Subseries A: 3.5 inch X 4.5 inch,1930, 1931
    - Anchor bridge 1117 in Ceder Hill, Connecticut (near New Haven) looking east. Smoke from a fire burning in the center of the tracks is in the background. A wall lines the lower section of the tracks on the right side of the photo. On the left side of the tracks stands a signal station. This image was taken in the same location as the previous photo (91),April 1931 (Box 3:92)
    - Bridgeport, Connecticut, River Crossing looking east. A very tall catenary bridge is in focus in the center of the image,April 1931 (Box 3:93)
    - Devon, Connecticut, river crossing looking north. The river water is in the foreground. Three tall catenary bridges along with the railroad track bridges span the center ground of the image horizontally,April 1931 (Box 3:94)
    - Devon, Connecticut, river crossing looking east. This photo has a view from the railroad tracks looking through the bridges,April 1931 (Box 3:95)
    - South Norwalk, Connecticut, river crossing looking east. A tall catenary bridge is the focus of the image. Industrial buildings are visible on the left side of the image,April 1931 (Box 3:96)
    - South Norwalk, Connecticut, westerly high tower, power supply for the drawbridge catenary. The image is a close-up view of the tower metalwork,April 1931 (Box 3:97)
    - Westport, Connecticut, river crossing looking east. The tall catenary bridge is in central focus. To the left and right stand railroad platforms,April 1931 (Box 3:98)
    - Bronx, New York, river crossing towers. On the left side of the track stands a small railroad building. One person stands on the left railroad track next to the building. A railroad bridge stands behind the catenary tower,June 1931 (Box 3:99)
  - Subseries B: 5 inch X 4 inch,n.d.
    - Anchor bridge under construction in an unknown location. Four men work on the top of the anchor bridge, two men stand on the tracks to the left of the construction, four men stand to the right on the tracks, and six people stand in a group on the side walk that runs alongside the left track,n.d. (Box 4:100)
    - View shows crew on an early wire train erecting messenger wires for compound catenary. Appears to be on the 4-track main line east of Stamford, Connecticut, but may be Harlem River Branch. Two men stand on the top of the anchor bridge, two stand on top of a construction car, two stand on a flatbed car, five stand on the track, and one operates a crane car, [ca. 1913] (Box 4:101)
    - Anchor bridge in an unknown location with triangular catenary wires in focus over railroad tracks,n.d. (Box 4:102)
    - Anchor bridge 886 between Devon, Connecticut, and Woodmont, Connecticut, with catenary wires in focus,n.d. (Box 4:103)
    - Anchor bridge in an unknown location with transformers connected to triangular catenary,n.d. (Box 4:104)
  - Subseries C: 7 inch X 5 inch,n.d.
    - Anchor bridge with catenary in an unknown location,n.d. (Box 4:105)
    - Anchor bridge with triangular catenary in an unknown location. The railroad tracks cut through rocky terrain with a residential area to the right of the tracks,n.d. (Box 4:106)
- Series III: Flexible Negatives, n.d., 1908, 1912-1914, 1919-1921, 1930-1931, 1933
  - Subseries A: 9 inch X 7 inch, 1921, 1930, 1933
    - Electrical switch generator inside a brick room. This is possibly a nitrate negative,1921 (Box 5:107)
    - Cos Cob, Connecticut, power plant. The image contains a view from above of eight large electrical machines spanning the length of a large concrete room,1930 (Box 5:108)
    - Cos Cob, Connecticut, power plant, from a different view. This image contains a two-story high round piece of machinery that has a walkway surrounding it, 1930 (Box 5:109)
    - Cos Cob, Connecticut, power plant, back-bus structure row of oil circuit-breakers, 1930 (Box 5:110)
    - Cos Cob, Connecticut, power plant, 22 KV circuit-breakers in switch house, 1930 (Box 5:111)
    - Cos Cob, Connecticut, power plant, 22 KV bus over traction-power transformers, 1930 (Box 5:112)
    - Cos Cob, Connecticut, power plant, local service transformers, 1930 (Box 5:113)
    - Cos Cob, Connecticut, power plant, a view from the outside of the building,1930 (Box 5:114)
    - Cos Cob, Connecticut, power plant. A view of two large cement pools of water outside the building,1930 (Box 5:115)
    - Cos Cob, Connecticut, power plant, a wide view of the building, including a New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad car,1930 (Box 5:116)
    - View look west toward Cos Cob Power Plant from across Mianus River. Shows hopper car unloading track, coal conveyor and storage pile, coal barge pierand coal leg for unloading coal barges, 1930 (Box 5:117)
    - Another view of the Cos Cob, Connecticut power plant from across the Mianus River. In the right side of the image a train is passing by the plant,1930 (Box 5:118)
    - Another view of the Cos Cob, Connecticut, power plant from across the Mianus River,1930 (Box 5:119)
    - Another inside view of the Cos Cob, Connecticut, power plant. This is another image of the two-story large machinery with the circular walkway surrounding it,1930 (Box 5:120)
    - Another view of outdoor concrete water pools at the Cos Cob, Connecticut, power plant,1930 (Box 5:121)
    - Another wide view from across the railroad track of the Cos Cob, Connecticut, power plant,1930 (Box 5:122)
    - A different exposure of the view from across the railroad track of the Cos Cob, Connecticut, power plant,1930 (Box 5:123)
    - New Haven, Connecticut, heat plant. The image is taken from a distance and includes railroad tracks that cross in front of the building,1930 (Box 5:124)
    - Another view of the New Haven, Connecticut, heat plant. The image is taken from a distance and includes railroad tracks that cross in front of the building,1930 (Box 5:125)
    - New Haven, Connecticut, heat plant, a closer view of the building and its smoke stacks,1930 (Box 5:126)
    - An interior view of the New Haven, Connecticut, heat plant. The image includes multiple banks of machinery filling a three-story room,1930 (Box 5:127)
    - A closeup view of banks of machinery inside the New Haven, Connecticut, power plant,1930 (Box 5:128)
    - OB installation E cut, possibly in New Haven, Connecticut. The image contains a close-up view of an anchor bridge crossing railroad tracks with signal station 78 in cut east of the New Haven station,July 28, 1933 (Box 5:129)
    - OB installation E cut, possibly in New Haven, Connecticut. This image is a closer view of the anchor bridge and includes a train passing through on the left of the image,July 28, 1933 (Box 5:130)
  - Subseries B: 4.5 inch X 3.5 inch, nitrate negatives, n.d., 1908, 1912-1914, 1919-1920, 1931
    - View looking east from Stamford, Connecticut, station. Note baggage cars stored at right, in yard off Atlantic and Manhattan Streets, 1908 (Box 6:131)
    - Stamford, Connecticut to Cos Cob, Connecticut, track. The image includes a view of a railroad bridge as well as of triangular catenary wires connected to anchor bridges that hold transformers,1908 (Box 6:132)
    - Unknown location between Stamford, Connecticut, and New Rochelle, New York,February 2, 1912 (Box 6:133)
    - New Haven, Connecticut, catenary and right of way,February 2, 1912 (Box 6:134)
    - View of possibly the Westchester yard, Harlem River Branch,February 2, 1912 (Box 6:135)
    - View of possibly the Westchester yard, Harlem River Branch, n.d. (Box 6:136)
    - View of possibly the Westchester yard, Harlem River Branch. The image was taken from the top of a railroad car, n.d. (Box 6:137)
    - Catenary and anchor bridge over a railroad track. Fences are on either side of the railroad track,n.d. (Box 6:138)
    - View of freight cars and catenary construction in Mount Vernon, New York, freight yard. There is a New York, Westchester & Boston Railway viaduct in the background [Note: the New York, Westchester & Boston Railway was a NHRR subsidiary in Westchester county with 2-track branches that ran from Port Chester, New York, and White Plains, New York, to a junction at Columbus Avenue in Mount Vernon, New York. It ran as 4 tracks to a connection with the Harlem River Branch (SS8) in the Bronx, terminating at Harlem River. All built as a high-capacity railroad with 11,000 volt AC electrification for multiple unit car operation. It opened 1912, was abandoned in 1937 and scrapped during World War II],[ca. 1920] (Box 6:139)
    - Horses pulling a cart under a catenary. A workman stands on a cart in front of the horses,n.d. (Box 6:140)
    - Catenary wires and anchor bridges in an unknown location,n.d. (Box 6:141)
    - Two men standing by a railroad track near an anchor bridge in an unknown location. Trains sit on railroad tracks behind the men,n.d. (Box 6:142)
    - Catenary wires above a railroad yard in an unknown location,n.d. (Box 6:143)
    - Catenary wires above a railroad track in an unknown location. A train sits on the track and stretches into the background,n.d. (Box 6:144)
    - View showing catenary at end of car float apron at Oak Point [Note: a carfloat is the bridge-like part of a "float bridge"; the pier structure that transfers cars onto carfloats (railroad car barges) for movement between rail/marine terminals. There were many types of float bridges, having the common characteristic of providing a movable, hinged apron that made up for variations in the height of the carfloat deck relative to the yard tracks due to tidal changes, as well as the twisting and vertical movement of the carfloat itself as strings of heavy freight cars (as many as 22 per float) were added or removed], n.d. (Box 6:145)
    - View showing catenary at end of carfloat apron at Oak Point, n.d. (Box 6:146)
    - Catenary wires and anchor bridges over a railroad track in an unknown location,n.d. (Box 6:147)
    - Views showing compound catenary at Pelham Bay drawbridge on Harlem River Branch. Note high transmission towers at drawbridge to raise power feeders above sailing ship masts, n.d. (Box 6:148)
    - View looking east toward anchor bridge 245 and interlocking tower SS27 at entrance to Byram multiple unit car yard, n.d. (Box 6:149)
    - View looking east toward Byram, Connecticut, from catenary bridge 262 in Port Chester, New York, n.d. (Box 6:150)
    - An anchor bridge holding transformers near an industrial area in an unknown location,n.d. (Box 6:151)
    - View looking east showing signal tower SS25 at catenary bridge 167 between Mamaroneck, New York, and Rye, New York. [There is damage on the top left and bottom right corners. The negative is brittle and shows some shrinking], n.d. (Box 6:152)
    - View of wire train on 4-track main line east of Stamford, Connecticut, erecting messenger wires for compound catenary. The image includes a New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad work car with a crane and several workmen standing around it,April 4, 1913 (Box 6:153)
    - View of wire train on 4-track main line east of Stamford, Connecticut, erecting messenger wires for compound catenary,April 4, 1913 (Box 6:154)
    - View of wire train on 4-track main line east of Stamford, Connecticut, erecting messenger wires for compound catenary. This view is taken from behind the platform on which the men work,April 4, 1913 (Box 6:155)
    - View of wire train on 4-track main line east of Stamford, Connecticut, erecting messenger wires for compound catenary. This image contains an empty railroad track and low hanging catenary wires on the right side of the track, April 4, 1913 (Box 6:156)
    - View of wire train on 4-track main line east of Stamford, Connecticut, erecting messenger wires for compound catenary. The image contains the empty railroad track and low hanging catenary wires and is taken from the opposite direction, April 4, 1913 (Box 6:157)
    - View of wire train on 4-track main line east of Stamford, Connecticut, erecting messenger wires for compound catenary. The worktrain in this image holds a spool that is distributing catenary wire outwards, April 4, 1913 (Box 6:158)
    - View of wire train on 4-track main line east of Stamford, Connecticut, erecting messenger wires for compound catenary, September 26, 1913 (Box 6:159)
    - Support for a future anchor bridge on the New Haven, Connecticut, right of way. The cement support is awaiting the construction of the anchor bridge,September 26, 1913 (Box 6:160)
    - A cement support at the foot of an anchor bridge on a New Haven, Connecticut, right of way, September 26, 1913 (Box 6:161)
    - Anchor bridges on a New Haven, Connecticut, right of way,September 26, 1913 (Box 6:162)
    - The wheels of a train, December 3, 1913 (Box 6:163)
    - View during construction of high transmission tower, used at drawbridges to raise power feeders above sailing ship masts. A crane lifts a beam into the air, three men stand on the central crossing of the anchor bridge, and four men stand under the anchor bridge on the railroad track, December 5, 1913 (Box 6:164)
    - New Haven, Connecticut, right of way and anchor bridge with transformers,December 5, 1913 (Box 6:165)
    - Bridgeport, Connecticut, anchor bridge,April 13, 1914 (Box 6:166)
    - South Norwalk, Connecticut anchor bridge and catenary wires,April 13, 1914 (Box 6:167)
    - View looking south toward Dock Yark in South Norwalk, Connecticut. [The top left corner of this negative is ripped and has been taped back to the rest of the negative with scotch tape on the non-emulsion side], April 13, 1914 (Box 6:168)
    - View looking north over train on Danbury Branch, adjacent to Dock Yard in South Norwalk, Connecticut. [The top right corner of this negative has been ripped and has been held together to the rest of the negative with scotch tape on the edge of the emulsion side], April 13, 1914 (Box 6:169)
    - Electrification equipment under a railroad bridge in an unknown location, April 1914 (Box 6:170)
    - Cos Cob, Connecticut, SW house, a view of electric machinery inside the building, October 14, 1919 (Box 6:171)
    - Cos Cob, Connecticut, SW house, another view of electric machinery inside the building, October 14, 1919 (Box 6:172)
    - Cos Cob, Connecticut, SW house, from a different angle. A view of electric machinery inside the building, October 14, 1919 (Box 6:173)
    - Cos Cob, Connecticut, SW house ceilings,October 14, 1919 (Box 6:174)
    - A railroad track with electrical poles running alongside in an unknown location. The negative has an oblong discoloration in its top left corner,August 1920 (Box 6:175)
    - A 300KW rotary with a DC end at Goodrum Substation near Porter, Indiana. The image is one of a group of images of equipment that the New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad bought for Nantasket, Massachusetts,August 14, 1920 (Box 6:176)
    - 300KW transformers starting a switch and rotary converter at Goodrum Substation near Porter, Indiana,August 14, 1920 (Box 6:177)
    - High tension busses, 300KW 3O transformers, and starting switchers at Goodrum Substation near Porter, Indiana,August 14, 1920 (Box 6:178)
    - Switchboard at Goodrum Substation near Porter, Indiana,August 14, 1920 (Box 6:179)
    - 45,000 volt oil circuit breaker, G.E. type F Form K10 (not for sale) at Goodrum Substation near Porter, Indiana,August 14, 1920 (Box 6:180)
    - Aluminum cell lightening arrester, type G.E., Form I, CAT number 72720 at Goodrum Substation near Porter, Indiana,August 14, 1920 (Box 6:181)
    - 300KW rotary converters in the Goodrum Substation (AC end), near Porter, Indiana. This negative is discolored through the center area,August 14, 1920 (Box 6:182)
    - Installing freight lead new Cedar Hill Yard, east of New Haven, Connecticut. The image includes several men working down the length of the track,September 19, 1920 (Box 6:183)
    - Nantasket, Massachusetts, power station number 1. Three men stand in front of the building,September 24, 1920 (Box 6:184)
    - Erection of the Milford Bridge over the New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad in Milford, Connecticut,1931 (Box 6:185)
    - Erection of the Milford Bridge over the New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad in Milford, Connecticut. A crane lifts a part of the bridge over the heads of four people, one of which may be a child. This negative is discolored in the center,1931 (Box 6:186)
    - Erection of the Milford Bridge over the New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad in Milford, Connecticut. A different view of a crane lifting a portion of the bridge over the heads of three people. A large discoloration crosses half the negative,1931 (Box 6:187)
    - Erection of the Milford Bridge over the New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad in Milford, Connecticut, a view from farther away. This negative has a stain over the bottom left corner,1931 (Box 6:188)
    - Erection of the Milford Bridge over the New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad in Milford, Connecticut in 1931, a different view,1931 (Box 6:189)
- Series IV: 35mm Developed Film, ca. 1959
  - It appears that all of the images on this roll, like 7:191, were taken on the same day, during a trip from Oak Point to Greenwich, to document facilities slated for abandonment. Roll 7:190 primarily shows towers SS27 and Byram multiple unit car yard subsequent to its closing in 1958 and just prior to the 1959 abandonment of Byram yard and removal of interlocking tower SS27, its main line switches, all yard catenary and bridges, and most yard tracks, ca. 1959 (Box 7:190)
    - Various views in area of New Rochelle Junction, New York, ca. 1959 (Box 7:190 (00, 0, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5))
    - View of transformers at interlocking tower SS26 in Rye, New York, ca. 1959 (Box 7:190 (7, 8, 9))
    - View looking east from base of interlocking tower SS27 toward entrance of Byram multiple unit car yard, ca. 1959 (Box 7:190 (10))
    - View looking east toward anchor bridge 245 and interlocking tower SS27 at entrance to Byram multiple unit car yard, ca. 1959 (Box 7:190 (11))
    - View looking west from anchor bridge 245 at SS27 (Byram multiple unit car yard) toward Life Savers factory in Port Chester, New York, ca. 1959 (Box 7:190 (12))
    - Wide views toward interlocking tower SS27 and Byram multiple unit car yard from opposite (north) side of mainline, ca. 1959 (Box 7:190 (13, 14))
    - View toward interlocking tower SS27 from opposite (north) side of mainline with westbound EP-4 and train passing, ca. 1959 (Box 7:190 (15))
    - Close-in view of interlocking tower SS27 and transformers from opposite (north) side of mainline, ca. 1959 (Box 7:190 (16))
    - Ground level view of track switches looking toward Byram Yard throat from base of SS27 [Note: a throat is the point where the multiple tracks in a yard fan out through a series of track switches - literally the mouth (entrance/exit) of the yard. It is quite pronounced at the Byram yard, where about 8-10 MU storage tracks and a couple of freight sidings all come together to connect with the main line in front of tower SS27], ca. 1959 (Box 7:190 (17))
    - View of transformers at SS27 looking down from second floor of interlocking tower, ca. 1959 (Box 7:190 (18))
    - High-level views toward Byram multiple unit car yard from tower SS27, showing layout of yard and freight sidings, ca. 1959 (Box 7:190 (19, 20))
    - Views taken at SS28 and Greenwich, Connecticut, railroad station, ca. 1959 (Box 7:190 (21, 22))
  - This roll consists of various scenes on the Harlem River Branch, possibly taken in connection with a NHRR study (ca. 1959) proposing the abandonment and removal of certain main line tracks, ca. 1959 (Box 7:191)
    - Various views of track and catenary structures between Oak Point and New Rochelle Junction on Harlem River Branch, ca. 1959 (Box 7:191 (1-22))
- Series V: 35mm Mounted Slides, consisting primarily of scenes along the electrified single-track Danbury Branch, and views of catenary modifications and other construction at New Rochelle Junction in connection with the Interstate 95 highway overpass construction, n.d., 1959, 1964
  - Subseries A: Black & White, n.d.
    - Close-up image of a bus, KVA, type C,n.d. (Box 8:192)
    - Close-up of outdoor electrical equipment above a town street,n.d. (Box 8:193)
    - Close-up image of electrical equipment, including a bus and two units labeled BE and BF1,n.d. (Box 8:194)
    - Image of a group of outdoor electrification equipment with a danger sign posted on it,n.d. (Box 8:195)
    - A railroad bridge over water with anchor bridges and catenary running above it,n.d. (Box 8:196)
    - A railroad bridge over water with a tall anchor bridge at its end connected to catenary,n.d. (Box 8:197)
    - A tall anchor bridge next to water with catenary stretching over the railroad track,n.d. (Box 8:198)
    - Catenary wires over a railroad track in a wooded area,n.d. (Box 8:199)
    - Catenary wires over a railroad track in a wooded area,n.d. (Box 8:200)
    - A complicated array of catenary over a transformer,n.d. (Box 8:201)
    - A close-up view of wires closely stretched across a block-like piece of electric equipment,n.d. (Box 8:202)
    - Two men standing on a railroad track inside a tunnel or under a bridge with wires running along the top of the wall next to them,n.d. (Box 8:203)
    - Another view of two men standing on a railroad track inside a tunnel or under a bridge with wires running along the top of the wall,n.d. (Box 8:204)
    - A man holding a long metal piece of equipment in a tunnel or under a bridge,n.d. (Box 8:205)
    - Catenary over a railroad track with a danger sign on an electric pole next to the track,n.d. (Box 8:206)
    - Three men standing on a platform next to a railroad track with catenary wires above the track,n.d. (Box 8:207)
    - Complicated arrangement of catenary between two electrical poles standing on either side of a railroad track,n.d. (Box 8:208)
    - Catenary over a railroad track with a danger sign to the right of the track,n.d. (Box 8:209)
    - Catenary over a railroad track in an industrial area,n.d. (Box 8:210)
    - Catenary over a railroad track in a populated area,n.d. (Box 8:211)
    - A man walking between railroad tracks with catenary above him,n.d. (Box 8:212)
    - The last multiple unit passenger car on a New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad train under catenary with its pantograph raised,n.d. (Box 8:213)
    - A view of two New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad multiple unit train cars under catenary, n.d. (Box 8:214)
    - Catenary over a railroad yard,n.d. (Box 8:215)
    - New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad multiple unit car with its pantograph raised,n.d. (Box 8:216)
    - Three men standing next to New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad multiple unit passenger car 4434 with its pantograph raised. One of the men is crouching to see the underside of the railroad car,n.d. (Box 8:217)
    - Five men sit outside the New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad station in Danbury, Connecticut,n.d. (Box 8:218)
    - Nine men stand in front of the New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad station in Danbury, Connecticut,n.d. (Box 8:219)
    - A close-up view of a machine printing out a report,n.d. (Box 8:220)
    - The pantograph of a New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad multiple unit car connecting to the catenary above it,n.d. (Box 8:221)
    - Catenary over a railroad track in a wooded area,n.d. (Box 8:222)
    - Catenary over a railroad track in a wooded area,n.d. (Box 8:223)
    - Catenary over a railroad track in a wooded area,n.d. (Box 8:224)
    - An anchor bridge and catenary over a railroad track next to a parking lot,n.d. (Box 8:225)
    - Catenary over a railroad track in a wooded area,n.d. (Box 8:226)
    - Catenary over a small bridge that is crossing a railroad track,n.d. (Box 8:227)